We are going to be discussing about the forward-lookup zone and the reverse-lookup zone.
You know, basically, a DNA zone represents a domain name.
So in our demonstration, for example, we have a kelvglobile.com domain.
So the kelvglobile.com zone represents and holds the DNA record for a kelvglobile domains.
So the zones then becomes the authoritative source of information about the domain name managed by that zone.
So here you can see we have two zones that has been created.
We have, for example, we have the forward-lookup zone and the reverse-lookup zones.
So here we can see another forward-lookup zone.
If I just click on that, let me expand this for now.
You can see we have another forward-lookup zone.
We have, for example, we have the MSDC.kelvglobile.com, and we also have a kelvglobile domain.com domain name.
Where we have all the different records, you can see others would only have the host record,
and we have our name, the NS record, and also the start of authority record.
So every record that's all been created, for example, every host that's added to the machine,
we will each other be added to this kelvglobile.com automatically when the device is added to the domain.
So what are the difference between the forward-lookup zone, the other forward-lookup zone,
and here you can see we have the reverse-lookup zone, which of course we've not created
a very fast-lookup zone.
So if we look up zone, typically confess a name to an IP address or another name at some point.
The important part, though this is that you start with a name, and then we try that name,
get results on IP address in most cases.
So this zone can't contain all the recorded domain names to their IP address.
Just like I said, you can see we have all the IP address at the tab in listed here,
and also we have audio, because here is that all the type is a host record.
I also have the domain, the name of the host devices.
So let's give an example.
For example, when you type, when I type, the www.kelvglobile.com, you know, browse down.
The forward-lookup zone will be created on the IP address, that's IP address of www.kelvglobile.com,
will be returned, which is the IP address of that site.
So when I open the command prompt, let me just go to my start menu, tap CMD.
And I'm going to do an as-lookupkelvglobile.com, and hit enter.
Here you can see we have our name, and that is the IP address of this device.
When I do IP config, you can see that the IP address is going to return the IP address
as other IP address.
And I started the IP address the second server, that domain, the domain controller, too.
So when the forward-lookup zone is sent to a DNS server, the DNS server is set from a type
of source record associated with a host name provided by the request.
So an eight-time resource is a DNS record that can be used to point the domain name and host
name to a static IP address.
So here you can see, we have like just what I said, you can see that the one, five, five,
and one, four, four, one, five, four, a boot static, but these are the host record, and
this is zero one, and that this is zero two.
So on the other hand, the request-lookup zone contains all the records of the IP address
to the main.
It will be too easy to the final request-lookup as opposites of forward-lookup zone, but it is
true.
The host-lookup zone is used anytime you want to confirm an IP address to a name.
Let's give an example.
If a client want to find a host name for the IP address, for example, one-line two,
one-six-eight.one-one.one-five-four, the request-lookup zone we query, and we return the host
name of that device.
So it's going to return the host name of this device and not the IP address.
So the request-lookup zone contains the PTRO source record.
And a PTRO record allows doing a fast-lookup by pointing the IP address to the host domain
name.
When doing the request-lookup, this PTRO record I use to point a resource record to the
domain.